PRASANTH GOPI CH

Hyderabad, India 500081 | +91-8790262266 ,+966-508301136 | prasanthgopichagarlamudi@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I have accumulated extensive experience across various industries within both international and national markets. My background includes a proven track record in client acquisition, business development, and operations. I have successfully closed and managed significant accounts for major companies. With a total of six years and 3 Months of experience(6.3 Years), including five years(5 Years) in managerial roles, I have demonstrated a consistent ability to drive growth and achieve strategic objectives.

EXPERIENCE

10/08/2024 to 11/08/2022 Branch Head (24 Months)

HR International - Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

- International Manpower Recruitment(Blue/White Collar)
- Held a pivotal role as a Business Development Manager
- Managed and supervised all aspects of branch operations
- Successfully developed and executed business plans that drove remarkable sales growth.
- Utilized targeted marketing approaches to drive business growth
- Closed **long-term agreements** through skill full negotiation.
- · Achieved consistent growth in client acquisition.
- Managing onboarded clientele
- Provided comprehensive training to the sales and business development team

31/07/2022 to 01/06/2021 State Manager (13 months)

Alphatech - Bangalore, India

- I.T SAAS & Hardware Sales, Recruitment(B2B)
- Training & Monitoring of Sales Team
- State Team KPI & Performance management
- Implemented and executed streamlined branch operations management strategies, resulting in enhanced efficiency and productivity.
- H.R Operations Management
- Managed Team size of 40
- Developed ongoing programmes using good team communication and collaboration.

28/05/2021 to 1/06/2020 **Business Development Manager** (11 months,27 Days)

Extramarks - Hyderbad, India

- EDTECH Software Sales(B2B/B2C) for schools & University's
- Augmented sales value by upselling and cross-selling new products and services to existing customers.
- Surpassed sales and customer service targets, consistently exceeding established KPIs.
- Management of sales team (Team size of 20)
- Led backend operations for team sales
- Managed escalated client enquiries with exceptional professionalism and enthusiasm to maintain trust and reliability.

29/02/2020 to

ABDM (15 months)

1/11/2018

Phoenix India - Chennai, India

- International Export/Import sales(B2B/B2C)
- Initiated and executed **cold calling** campaigns to generate new business leads.
- Email Marketing
- · Lead generation
- Digital Campaign
- helping team to convert prospects in to clients
- · creating quotations estimation costs ,purchase orders etc

31/10/2018 to

BDE (12 Months)-

2/10/2017

Phoenix india - Chennai, India

- International Export/Import sales
- · cold calling
- · email marketing
- · building prospect pipeline

SKILLS

- Performance Management
- Systems implementation
- client acquisition
- negotiations
- B2B /B2C Sales
- Training and developing staff
- Workforce training and development
- Risk Management

- Supplier negotiation
- Multi-unit operations management
- People Management
- Strategic resource management
- Staff management
- Client Relationship Management
- Adaptive leadership
- Budget management
- C,D Level Client Interaction

EDUCATION

2023

Master of Business Administration: Human resource & Finance

Manipal University - Jaipur

• 3.56/4 Cgpa

2020

Bachelor of Science: Information Technology **Mahatma Gandhi University** - Chennai

• 86% in academics

LANGUAGES

English: First Language

English:	C2	Telugu:	C2
Proficient		Proficient	
Hindi:	C1	Tamil:	B2
Advanced		Upper Intermediate	
Arabic:	B2	Chinese (Mandarin):	B1
Llon on Interno alliate		lute massiliete	

Upper Intermediate

Intermediate

- TCS certified Trainer & Mentor
- Six Sigma Certified
- International k9 handler certificate

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- K9 Training
- Boxing
- photography

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Highest Revenue Generation state Head(alphatech india)
- 3 x Employee of the quarter
- International photopro award winner
- Closed 3 Million Dollar Deal

VISA'S

- H2B U.S(10 Years)
- Schengen Multi Visit (10 years)
- Russian Multi Entry(1 year)
- U.A.E Business Visa(2 years)
- K.S.A Business Visa(2 Years)
- Japan Multiple entry Tourist
- Singapore Tourist
- Republic of china Tourist